<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Thoughts</title>
 <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/"/>
 <updated>2018-10-16T23:21:30+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://blog.skryl.org</id>
 <author>
   <name>Alex Skryl</name>
   <email>aleksey.skryl@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>P53</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2015/01/15/p53/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2015/01/15/p53</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jack Thompson carefully placed Roger into his cage as Patrick Hughes entered the lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey Jack. Yuri missed our weekly. Any idea where he is?” asked the Director, looking concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?! He didn’t tell you?” replied Thompson, grinning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tell me what?” inquired Hughes, reaching for a chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“P53! It worked! It … more than worked!” said Thompson in an excited whisper.
He pulled up a chair next to Hughes, taking his time to contrive an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat, do you know why most living things don’t live forever?” Thompson asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hughes pondered the question for a second. “Assuming they don’t die
of disease or some unfortunate accident, it’s because they get old. Their cells
become less efficient with age, having to work just as hard only to get less
done. Current science blames it on DNA degradation, isn’t that right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes! It’s a fidelity problem!” exclaimed Thompson, his eyes widening with
excitement. “With every copy, our genome’s signal to noise ratio decreases,
causing the cellular machinery to alter its behavior slightly. Over time, these
small errors accumulate, usually leading to what we perceive as aging, and on
rare occasion causing cancer and other nasties. Now, let me ask you this,”
Thompson continued, “considering how universal senescence is, why do you think
that nature hasn’t come up with a fix?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hughes sighed, getting impatient. “It’s a diminishing returns problem if I
remember correctly. Complex organisms die from predation, disease, hunger, and a
myriad of other causes, making their chances of living to old age slim to none.
There is no evolutionary pressure to extend lifespan because animals don’t die
of old age, they die from being eaten by other animals.” Hughes
reached for a pen and a piece of paper. “Look here. If the probability of some
creature dying in the span of a single day is 1/1000, then the probability of
them surviving for 20 years is (999/1000)^(365*20)=0.067%, which is negligible.
So, as long as they reach maturity and reproduce well before then, evolution
will consider them fit. No reason to fix what’s not broken. Right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m very impressed Dr. Hughes!” said Thompson smiling. “Anyhow, this is where
P53 comes in. It is a retroviral gene therapy that was intended to be a cancer
vaccine. It improves transcription fidelity and adds new mutation-triggered
apoptosis pathways. A few things that nature overlooked. Here’s the kicker
though, after vaccination, our simulations show no sign of DNA degradation over
millennia. That’s thousands of years, Pat!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wait!” Hughes interrupted. “Am I to understand that the two of you
inadvertently created an immortality drug?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Roger is our first living test subject,” Thompson replied, glancing at the
white mouse on the other side of the room. “But if the simulations are accurate,
then he will outlive us all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who else knows about this?” Hughes asked, reaching for his phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Olovnikov, myself, and now you,” said Thompson. “Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Brian?” Hughes spoke into the handset, “Code 42, lock us down plea…” before
he finished his sentence, Yuri Olovnikov walked into the room. There was fear in
the man’s eyes but it was overshadowed by righteous determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“King of kings, Lord of lords; Who only hath immortality, dwelling in the light
which no man can approach unto…” Olovnikov mumbled, his voice trembling.
“Forgive me.” His fingers tensed into a fist and the lab was suddenly awash in a
brilliant white light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the dust from the explosion settled, a small white mouse ran out of the
rubble into the grassy underbrush nearby. He had a long life ahead of him.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Uncertainty</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2014/07/11/uncertainty/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2014/07/11/uncertainty</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Computer, report!” yelled the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, all primary systems are online but the star orientations do not match anything in my database.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What was our entry confidence?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was six nines, sir.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Captain Nurbek swallowed hard, “Show me the trajectory map.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looked like a water droplet in zero-g, slowly morphing while the computer was
busy plotting all the possible routes the ship may have taken to arrive here.
Nurbek was temporarily entranced by it’s beautiful complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost in thought, he recalled the great men of the past. Men who believed in a
deterministic universe, where one could predict the future by simply knowing
enough about the present. It was an idea that was hopelessly wrong, yet
perfectly seductive, because it made men feel like they could become gods. But
much to Man’s dismay, the true gods had other plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space has no shortcuts, he mused. Dreams of determinism died at the hands of
Quantum Mechanics and General Relativity. But would he be any less screwed if
the Universe was actually a Laplacian dream? No, it made no difference.
Determinism was still susceptible to chaos, the law of nature which was
responsible for his current snafu. Chaos is what made the long jumps effectively
unpredictable and extremely sensitive to small errors in entry calculations. He
simply made a wrong guess in a profession where bad guesses were the worst
possible offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six nines. Six fucking nines. He needed at least nine nines for a jump of this
magnitude. But he was in the middle of a war zone. Any longer and the ship would
have been blown to bits. Would waiting another second really have killed him? He
would never know. All he knew was, he would be looking at the familiar starscape
of the Virgo Cluster had he waited. Instead he was here. Somewhere. Nowhere, as
far as the computer was concerned. He glanced back at the rotating shape on the
screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He suddenly remembered his old physics professor running different colored
threads through a blob of silly putty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Imagine the strings are flight trajectories and the putty is our little cosmos.
Where would you need to enter the blob in order to come out with the red
string?” asked the professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where the red string enters,” I replied, not seeing where he was going with
this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What if you messed up your calcs and entered at the green one next to it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then you would come out close to your intended destination, where the green one
does.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right,” he said, “this is how space travel would work if space was linear. You
could make a mistake and still get to where you were going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He mashed the putty in his hands for a few seconds, keeping the entry points of
the strings untouched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where do the two strings exit now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Far apart,” I said after locating the strings in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what would happen if you messed up your entry calcs in this case?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d be screwed,” I responded with an air of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good, this is how real space travel works. Except the strings are
infinitesimally thin, and your room for error is almost non-existent. The lesson
here is, get your calcs right, always! And then maybe well get to have this
conversation again some day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurbek snapped back to reality, finally gathering the courage to ask the
lingering question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Computer, based on your survey of the cluster, will we make it out of here
alive?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computer paused for a few seconds, as if to heighten the suspense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unlikely, sir, but I could never be certain.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>NAND to MIPS</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/08/nand-to-mips/"/>
   <updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/08/nand-to-mips</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A crash course in computer architecture. This is a presentation I put together during my time at &lt;a href=&quot;https://recurse.com&quot;&gt;Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt; to introduce my fellow Recursers to basic CPU design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//slides.com/skryl/nand-to-mips/embed&quot; width=&quot;576&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharebuttons&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;reddit&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/submit?url=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/08/nand-to-mips/&amp;amp;title=NAND%20to%20MIPS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-reddit-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;hn&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/submitlink?u=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/08/nand-to-mips/&amp;amp;t=NAND%20to%20MIPS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-hacker-news-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?via=_skryl_&amp;amp;url=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/08/nand-to-mips/&amp;amp;text=NAND%20to%20MIPS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-twitter-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Kinesis Conversion</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/07/the-kinesis-conversion/"/>
   <updated>2013-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/07/the-kinesis-conversion</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to undertake yet another keyboard modification project. You may be familiar with the popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Kinesis_Advantage&quot;&gt;Kinesis Advantage&lt;/a&gt; ergonomic keyboard. Yes, the one with the crazy contoured shape. Well, mine has been lying dormant in the back of the closet for months due to the fact that I hate the feel of the Cherry Brown switches which it ships with from the factory (you can get it with Cherry Reds also but I do not like them either). Having taken a peek inside the case of the Advantage, a potential switch swap (to Cherry Blues) did not appear too difficult, so I finally made the move to order some parts and do the swap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To figure out what parts I needed for the swap I simply called tech support and asked. The support guy I spoke to was extremely helpful. He told me exactly what I would need to do the switch swap and made the order for me. It came out to around $14 total and he even threw in a free set of blue home row key caps! This was probably the best tech support experience I have ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-parts-list&quot;&gt;The parts list&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;68 new Cherry Blue switches - This is the most expensive part of the swap. Unless you can get a better deal, these run around $1 per switch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;68 small diodes - $1 total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left and Right PCB - $7 each&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left and Right plastic key support - Free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Left and Right thumb cluster PCB and ribbon cable - Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools-you-will-need&quot;&gt;Tools you will need&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phillips screwdriver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soldering iron and an optional desoldering iron (or desoldering braid)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have all the parts, begin by unscrewing the bottom of the Kinesis shell and seperate the two halves by unplugging the USB controller cable from the main PCB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pull out the main key wells by unplugging the white ribbon cable and removing 3 screws from each side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the switches in the key wells are first mounted inside the plastic support and only then soldered onto the flexible PCB. Do the same when building the replacement key wells by inserting all the switches into the plastic support before doing any soldering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure all the switch housings are snapped into the support and none of the switches are crooked or rotated incorrectly (see photos).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the switches at the bottom of the finger strips, solder each one to the PCB going up the strip (You may need to remove the bottom most switches temporarily to make it easier to align the PCB as I have done in the photo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the switches have been soldered to the PCB you will need to add small diodes to the bottom of each switch with the black stripe facing left. These diodes are not visible on the stock PCBs since they are built into the stock Cherry switches (your switches most likely do not include the diodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The diodes are oriented the same way on both the left and right PCBs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the diodes are in place you are done with one key well. Now repeat the above steps for the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the thumb cluster keys are PCB mounted (with no supports), there are two ways to swap their switches. One way is to simply rebuild each thumb cluster from spare parts like we did with the key wells. The other (possibly quicker) way is to pop off the key caps and take apart each switch, replacing the insides with those of the replacement switches. Because I had the parts and the time I decided to build each cluster from parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building the thumb clusters is fairly self explanatory. Insert and solder all the switches. Then add the diodes and the ribbon cables and you are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tricky part is removal of the old thumb clusters. It requires the removal of the main PCB (a single screw in the middle) and desoldering the thumb cluster ribbon cables. (A $15 desoldering iron from Radio Shack will make your life much easier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replace the old thumb clusters with the new ones, re-attach the main PCB and re-assemble the main key wells. You are officially done with the swap, but before putting everything back together make sure to connect the keyboard to a computer and test each key individually to confirm that it works (using a tool like KeyCodes for OSX).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20130907/19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Process 11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The swap takes a couple of hours and is well worth it if you prefer the feel of the Cherry Blue switches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharebuttons&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;reddit&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/submit?url=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/07/the-kinesis-conversion/&amp;amp;title=The%20Kinesis%20Conversion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-reddit-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;hn&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/submitlink?u=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/07/the-kinesis-conversion/&amp;amp;t=The%20Kinesis%20Conversion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-hacker-news-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?via=_skryl_&amp;amp;url=http://blog.skryl.org/2013/09/07/the-kinesis-conversion/&amp;amp;text=The%20Kinesis%20Conversion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-twitter-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sight</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2013/01/11/sight/"/>
   <updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2013/01/11/sight</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was Veleriy Zyvotov’s work that finally brought an end to the AI winter. The
Z-papers, as they became known, were a tour de force in cortical theory and
marked the beginnings of the Brain Decade. For the next dozen or so years
scientists would scrutinize and map every nook and cranny of the human neocortex
in an attempt to emulate all of its quirks. The visual system was naturally one
of the first to be dissected and trivialized. It turned out to be fairly easy to
get a feed, an image that is, of what a person saw in their mind’s eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech quickly caught up with the research and the first HoloSight came out
less than two years after the academic research. All you had to do was tuck the
thing behind your ear, remember something vivid, and poof, there it was, in
colorful holography. Problem was, most people don’t remember too well, so the
pictures often appeared fuzzy, faceless, or distorted in a myriad ways. Still,
there were a few whose memories held perfect impressions of reality and whose
imaginations could paint fiction just as clearly. They were called Seers and
they became the Beethovens and Mozarts of the modern world.  Some were
classically trained, having had to retard their vision with a wooden brush and a
pastel set, but most were simply dreamers who would have never survived the
urban rat race had they lived in the decades of past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the demand grew, Sight became bidirectional and could pump all five senses
from one person to the next. You could chain together a few or broadcast to
millions, as long as there was enough bandwidth and memory to maintain the
integrity of the feed. Virtual Worlds became a dime a dozen and many liked to
jack in and tune out. They wanted to own suburban homes and have four kids, not
live in Megablocks, breathe polluted air, and have to win a lottery in order to
copulate. Sight gave them the escape they dreamed of and for a while they went
back and forth between reality and utopia. They worked for food and lived for
Sight. But something strange began to happen as more and more addicts checked
out while on the wire. Some of their avatars persisted, the machines having had
enough time to reverse engineer their identities, their souls. The bodies died
but the minds kept on living. It was a welcome feature. Soon enough regular
folks began taking their own lives, some even took their families with them.
There was a suicide streak that went on for years and for the first time in
modern history the population plummeted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know what happens when three quarters of the world’s population takes a
dirt nap? You’d think it would be a catastrophe but it actually turned out quite
alright. The religious nuts were the first to go. They called it “Heaven on
Earth” and didn’t wait long to follow their beloved ministers to an imaginary
Salvation. The oppressed, the cynical, and the power hungry went next. Everyone
now had a choice to make, and those who stuck around all had something in
common. They were motivated and ready to start over. After a while, clean water
and air stopped being a commodity and there was enough food to feed everyone.
With a universal single mindedness we began to terraform, bringing the Earth
back to the way she was when the dinosaurs roamed, blue and green, not red and
grey.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Forgotten</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2012/10/31/forgotten/"/>
   <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2012/10/31/forgotten</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was 3am. I woke up thinking of her. I had no idea who she was but her
presence was overwhelming. Like a black hole in my subconscious she tore
away the foundations of any structured thought. All effort to escape her grasp
was futile and ended in a constellation of unfamiliar memories. Her voice, her
scent, her face… a dizzying deja vu of someone I have never met.
  The ring of the telephone broke through the silence.
  Stumbling out of bed I reached for the handset.
  “Come over”, she said in a calm, stern voice.
I remained mute, unable to shake the fog and confusion of the persistent dream.
She hung up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I waited in anticipation, still dazed by the slew of unfamiliar memories running
through my mind. The leafs began to stir as she came into view. Her dark
hair fell down to her shoulders where a black dress was struggling to hold
on to her slender body. As she walked, the wind played with her hair and her
dress waved in desperation. She resonated with the darkness. She was gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Drive,” she said, as she slid into the back seat.
I obeyed. I didn’t know the way but I felt a strange sense of familiarity
guiding me. It was as though threads of memory were being pulled out of some
cerebral abyss and weaved back into my consciousness. With every turn she
resurrected a part of me which I had long forgotten, piecing together a life I
never knew I had. The picture continued to grow clearer, until I could finally
make out our destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was gone. I stood in the middle of a forested road, staring at a tall pine
tree which lay across both lanes. I remembered sitting on my knees next to that
same tree, soaking wet, holding her head as she took quick shallow breaths. Her
face was covered in lacerations, glass shards protruding from her porcelain
skin, draining her of life. I couldn’t stop the bleeding but I did my best to
slow it down. Leaving her side to search for the phone meant a quick death, not
searching for it meant certain death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They said she would be OK… She died on the way to the hospital.
They said my memory would come back within a few weeks… It has been five years.
They tried to convince me of who I was… I didn’t believe them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stepped over the fallen tree. The road ahead was dark, but having her by my
side again gave me the courage to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quest for the Perfect Click</title>
   <link href="http://blog.skryl.org/2012/08/10/quest-for-the-perfect-click/"/>
   <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.skryl.org/2012/08/10/quest-for-the-perfect-click</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While searching for reasonably priced &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overclock.net/forum/373-keyboards/491752-official-mechanical-keyboard-guide.html&quot;&gt;mechanical keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to pillage the archives of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekhack.org&quot;&gt;keyboard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net&quot;&gt;enthusiast&lt;/a&gt; community to learn what I could about what makes these bad boys click, and to put together a list of contenders I wanted to test personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some searching, sorting and filtering I decided to make my first buy. A Leopold &lt;a href=&quot;http://elitekeyboards.com/products.php?sub=leopold,tenkeyless&amp;amp;pid=fc200rtab&quot;&gt;FC200R&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Cherry_MX_Brown&quot;&gt;Cherry Brown&lt;/a&gt; switches. On paper, the brown switch is perfect. It provides tactility without much noise, and features a low key activation force, making it easy to glide over keys without any effort but with all the assurance of accuracy. I ordered the FC200R from &lt;a href=&quot;http://elitekeyboards.com&quot;&gt;EliteKeyboards&lt;/a&gt; and it arrived later that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that jumped out at me when unpacking the $100 keyboard was its exceptional build quality. At almost 1kg the FC200R is no Apple Bluetooth Keyboard. Instead, it feels like a small typewriter sitting on your keyboard tray. The bezel is slightly rounded and made of high quality plastic; very little space is wasted or non functional. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://elitekeyboards.com/products.php?sub=leopold,tenkeyless&amp;amp;pid=fc200rtabn&quot;&gt;Otaku&lt;/a&gt; version of the FC200R takes the minimalism a step further and removes the key labels to leave you with a subtle but elegant typing instrument. No corners are cut in the manufacturing of this keyboard. It has no apparent wobble or structural abnormalities, the rubber feet are well placed and properly glued onto the base, and the USB cable is removable in case you’re unhappy with its length. There was not a thing about the device that made me regret dropping a hundred bucks on it. That is, until I started typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idolized Cherry Brown switches left something to be desired. They felt all wrong and I wasnt sure why. The activation force wasn’t prohibitive, the noise level was reasonable, and the tactile bump was present when slowly depressing the switch. At normal typing speeds however, the bump just created unnecessary friction instead of acting as a tactile feedback mechanism. Typing on the Cherry Browns felt like driving a Ferrari with the parking break up. I tried it for a couple weeks, and still wallowing in dissapointment, dropped another $100 on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://elitekeyboards.com/products.php?sub=leopold,tenkeyless&amp;amp;pid=fc200rcabn&quot;&gt;Cherry Blue version&lt;/a&gt; of the Leopold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Cherry_MX_Blue&quot;&gt;Cherry Blues&lt;/a&gt; were noisy, as expected. Except the noise they make isn’t of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ujd6l_9TUmU&quot;&gt;typing like a boss&lt;/a&gt; variety that comes from the Model M’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Buckling_spring&quot;&gt;buckling springs&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, it is more akin to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RYK03ltDcqM&quot;&gt;typing on egg shells&lt;/a&gt;. Assuming you can get past the high pitched clicking, the Cherry Blue is a big improvement in terms of feel. It’s tactile click is snappy and brief, giving you immediate feedback, instead of the scratching feeling that the Cherry Browns induce. All I needed now was for Cherry Corp to make some kind of freak hybrid switch with the tactility of the Blues and the sound of the Browns. Lo and behold, after a few hours of research, I found out about a relatively rare &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Cherry_MX_Clear&quot;&gt;Cherry Clear&lt;/a&gt; switch. It has a larger tactile bump than the Browns, in addition to a much stiffer spring. I wasn’t interested in the extra stiffness, but I was desperate for some tactility. It just so happens that Cherry Corp uses identical switch housings in the many variations of the MX Switch. This makes it possible to pry open the 87 tiny black boxes and replace their brown innards with those of a donor clear switch, producing, what the internets christened the &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Cherry_MX_Ergo_Clear&quot;&gt;Ergo Clear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-swap&quot;&gt;The Swap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this knowlege I jumped on the classifieds board of GeekHack and dropped some hard earned cash on a donor Cherry MX8100 which uses the revered Cherry Clears. My hands were itching to start the project but my enthusiasm was quickly grounded by the bleak, dark reality of a forum thread which outlined the switch replacement process. Swapping the switches on the FC200R requires desoldering every single one of the 87 switches, pulling them out of the metal backplate, replacing their insides, and resoldering them one by one once the stem swap is complete. Nevertheless, with both keyboards already taken apart on my work table there was no turning back. I cleared my schedule for the day, pulled out my trusty soldering iron, ran to the nearest Radio Shack to buy a desoldering braid, and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cherry-mx8100-donor-board&quot;&gt;The Cherry MX8100 Donor Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the FC200R, The MX8100 has PCB mounted switches, meaning that it is unnecessary to desolder them in order to unlock their housings and harvest their organs. Popping them open is relatively easy using only a small flathead screwdriver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Leopold is held together by three screws and a few plastic clips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the bezel was removed, it was time to attack the PCB. The two solder points around each black insert are the legs of the switch, which is where the desoldering should happen. A word of caution. Unless you’re a wizzard with a desoldering braid I would highly recommend investing in a desoldering iron with a suction bulb, which is ~ $10 at your local Radio Shack. It will save you a great deal of time. If you do decide to go with the braid ( a mistake I made ) you need to make sure to remove all the solder on each contact, leaving the leg of the switch unobstructed and easy to pull out (I learned this the hard way as you will see in a bit ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desoldering iron with a rubber vacuum bulb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the switches are desoldered, removing them is a matter of a prying and pressing firmly on the round switch insert on the back of the PCB. Once again, if the switch doesn’t want to give, make sure that both legs are desoldered completely. Don’t try to force it, you WILL damage the PCB (scarrier than it sounds, see below for PCB repair).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replacing the internals is a simple, mechanical, and appropriately time consuming task. Just pop the swtich open, remove the brown stem, and replace it with a clear one. Replace the spring as well if you prefer the stiff feeling of the stock Cherry Clears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the switches have been put back together, insert them into the back plate, making sure that the legs slide back into their original positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resoldering should be much easier than desoldering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to damage the PCB contacts when forcefully removing the switches from the back plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to fix the damaged contact simply follow the path to it’s destination and solder a thin wire from the switch leg directly to the end contact of the wire path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the switches have been resoldered, but before reassembling any further, make sure to plug the board in and test every key. Use an app such as KeyCodes for OSX to make sure all key presses register. Fix any bad contacts and put the keyboard back together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
So was it all worth it? At first I wasn’t sure. The springs from the Cherry Browns seemed a bit weak for the larger tactile hump of the Clears, which caused the switch to be sluggish on its way up. However, this did not affect real world performance like I thought it would. The switches feel great. The Ergo Clear is what the brown should have been. The only improvement I’d recommend for this mod is to use a slightly stiffer spring (+5cN or so). The Cherry Blue might prove to be a good candidate in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have typed on quite a few other mechanical keyboards since the arrival of my first Leopold. In the end, the Cherry Blues ended up growing on me and are currently my favorite switch. The Ergo Clear board is what I use for work on account of the noise. As far as the layout and construction goes, I love the 87 key form factor and the build quality of the FC200R. I own three Leopolds (Blue, Ergo Clear, Red) and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://elitekeyboards.com/products.php?sub=topre_keyboards,rftenkeyless&amp;amp;pid=rf_se1700&quot;&gt;Realforce 86U&lt;/a&gt; Topre board. If you type for a living and have never owned a mechanical keyboard, there is no excuse not to invest in one. They come in all shapes and sizes, and can be easily resold for most of their retail value if for some reason you’re unsatisfied. Your hands will thank you and your coworkers will be jealous (or really annoyed). Happy Hacking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.skryl.org/assets/images/20120810/13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swap 13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sharebuttons&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;reddit&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/submit?url=http://blog.skryl.org/2012/08/10/quest-for-the-perfect-click/&amp;amp;title=Quest%20for%20the%20Perfect%20Click&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-reddit-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;hn&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/submitlink?u=http://blog.skryl.org/2012/08/10/quest-for-the-perfect-click/&amp;amp;t=Quest%20for%20the%20Perfect%20Click&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-hacker-news-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?via=_skryl_&amp;amp;url=http://blog.skryl.org/2012/08/10/quest-for-the-perfect-click/&amp;amp;text=Quest%20for%20the%20Perfect%20Click&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;i class=&quot;fab fa-twitter-square fa-2x&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
